A hitman and a salesman walk into a bar...
The Matador is a action, comedy, crime film directed by Richard Shepard.
The life of Danny Wright, a salesman forever on the road, veers into dangerous and surreal territory when he
wanders into a Mexican bar and meets a mysterious stranger, Julian, who's very likely a hit man.
Their meeting sets off a chain of events that will change their lives forever, as Wright is suddenly thrust into
a far-from-mundane existence that he takes to surprisingly well … once he gets acclimated to it.
Julian Noble, played by Pierce Brosnan.
Danny Wright, played by Greg Kinnear.
Carolyn 'Bean' Wright, played by Hope Davis.
Genevive, played by Portia Dawson.
Phil Garrison, played by Adam Scott.
The Matador, played by Israel Tellez.
The Matador is a 2005 black comedy crime film written and directed by
Richard Shepard, and starring Pierce Brosnan and Greg Kinnear.
The film was released on DVD on July 4, 2006, and
on HD DVD on December 19, 2006.
Brosnan received praise and was nominated for both a Golden Globe Award and a Saturn
Award for his performance as disillusioned, unstable hitman Julian Noble.
The film explores themes of mexico city, mexico,
hitman, midlife crisis, cocktail, stranger.
The tone is intense and lighthearted and emotional.